"越狱"前情提要...
Previously on Prison Break...
失去弟弟 给你的人生留下巨大的创伤
Losing a brother,the massive hole that leaves in your life.
和失去丈夫一样
Like the same massive hole
留下了巨大的创伤
losing a husband makes.
-你弟弟已经死了  -那这怎么解释
- Your brother's dead, Lincoln. - How do you explain that?
-林肯·布鲁斯  -雅各布
- Lincoln Burrows.- Jacob.
-林肯叔叔  -嘿
- Uncle Lincoln! ‭- Hey!
911吗 有人持枪入闯入了我的屋子
911. I have an armed intruder in my house.
我们触发了一些事...
We've awoken something...
一些想被藏起来的 跟迈克有关的事
something people are trying to hide about Michael.
我都不知道我们在跟谁拼命
I don't know who we're fighting.
我们去也门 把事情搞清楚
Let's go to Yemen and find out.
你他妈一点都不了解也门
You don't know a damn thing about Yemen.
那我就去找个了解也门的人
I'll find someone who does.
这个国家四分五裂了 每个人都想走
The country's falling apart. Everyone wants out.
欢迎加入内战
Welcome to the civil war.
快走 不然我们都得死
Come quickly, or we'll all be dead!
-中间人是谁来着  -一个叫希巴的女人
- Who's that contact again?- A woman named Sheba.
迈克尔惹上大麻烦了脱不开身
Michael's caught in the middle of something big.
坎尼尔·奥提斯
Kaniel Outis is
-可是个知名的恐怖分子  -我们安排
- a big-time terrorist. - We've arranged
去奥杰吉厄监狱探监
a visit to Ogygia Prison.
那意思是迈克尔在里面 吗
That mean Michael's in there?
迈克尔
Michael?
我的名字不是迈克尔 我也不认识你
My name isn't Michael, and I don't know who you are.
迈克 你在做什么 该死的
Michael, what are you doing, damn it?!
随着伊斯兰国部队靠近国会大厦
The fighting in Yemen intensified today
也门的战斗愈演愈烈
as ISIL forces get ever nearer to the capitol.
声称要接管这个国家
The rebels, who have the stated intent of taking over the country
建立伊斯兰国的反动派
and establishing a radical caliphate,
也下决心要让他们的领袖获释
are also bent on freeing their leader,
阿布·拉马尔 5年前被政府擒获
Abu Ramal, who was captured by the government five years ago.
拉马尔以其极端言行著称
Ramal is known for his extreme views and practices,
他把年轻女孩当性奴
from using young girls as sex slaves,
像中世纪执法一样公开斩首
to a medieval brand of justice that includes public beheadings
当街处决囚犯
and executions in the street.
拉马尔目前被关押在
Ramal is currently being held in
也门最臭名昭著的监狱 奥杰吉厄监狱
Yemen's most notorious penitentiary, Ogygia Prison.
就现在了
This is it.
维普 快点上来
Whip, get up here.
开始了吗
Is it happening?
你不会丢下我们不管 对吗
You are not going to leave us, are you?
如果反动派占领这座城市
If the rebels take the city,
我们死定了
we're dead.
你跟我们说了不下千次了
You've told us that a thousand times,
锡德 你老是问同样的问题 我的回答还不明白吗
Sid. You're a broken record. Is it clear?
好 我明白
Okay, it's clear.
维普 快
Whip. Come on.
我们出去... 你跟上
Let's go out... you follow.
快
Come on.
如果像别的越狱一样
Would have made it so much easier
就只有我跟你两个人 会不会容易很多
if it was just you and me like it was on all the other ones.
这次越狱没有任何环节容易
Nothing is easy on this one.
对 跟我说说
Yeah, tell me about it.
还有一分钟
One minute.
拿板子跨过缺口
Board spans the gap.
好
Okay.
毯子包着电线
Blanket covers the wire.
现在就等停电了
Now it's about those lights going out.
他24小时前没有闪过灯
He didn't flash it 24 hours before.
-本来应该有闪灯信号的  -有点信心
- That's supposed to be the signal. ‭- Have faith.
连续7天吗
Seven straight nights?
没有信号 灯也没熄过
No signal, no lights getting turned out?
伊斯兰国的攻击也越来越近了
Those strikes are getting closer, too.
探照灯没有熄
Those lights aren't going out.
-灯没有熄  -得回去了
- Lights aren't going out. - ‭Got to go back.
也许我们可以跑过去试试
Maybe make a run for it.
太远了 我们跑到缺口之前
Too much ground to cover. They'll shoot us down
-就被他们射杀  -那之后计划是什么 放弃还是等死
- before we make the gap - What's the plan then? Give up and die?
我不能再等多4年了
I can't wait another four years.
本来说好是一周内出去的
It was supposed to be one week.
波塞冬把我们留下来等死
Poseidon has left us here to die.
我们手上还有一张牌
‭We still got one card left to play.
我不想用掉 但已经准备用了
I didn't want to play it, but it's already in motion.
走吧
Let's go.
显然 坎尼尔·奥提斯因为对抗政府
Apparently, Kaniel Outis was thrown into Ogygia
被扔进了奥杰吉厄监狱
for crimes against the government.
不久后
Shortly after, he was captured
又试图逃跑 被扔进了单间
trying to escape, and thrown into solitary.
他们最近才把他放回多人间
They just released him into gen pop recently.
称他为迈克尔 好吗
Call him Michael, will you?
但为什么他看见我们的时候
But why didn't he acknowledge us
说不认识我们
when he saw us?
站住
Stop!
回来
Get back here!
有小孩在监视我们
Kid was spying on us.
在门垫下留了点东西
And he left something under the doormat.
是迈克尔的笔迹
It's Michael's handwriting.
这是他的标志 他在联系我们
This one's his calling card. He is reaching out to us.
他为什么这么神秘
But why is he being so mysterious?
以前 他也是不直接跟你说
Back in the day, he never
而是用密码的方式吗
talked to you straight, as in not in code?
他担心有人会拦截他的信息
He's worried about someone intercepting his message.
但那是什么意思
Yeah, but what does it mean?
我不知道 但我们应该知道
I don't know, but we're supposed to know.
-"光之酋长"  -光之酋长
- "Sheik of Light."- ‭Sheik of Light.
像是某个在山顶的男人
That sounds like a guy on a mountain peak
在跟上帝交流
communing with God.
我们得寻求帮助
Yeah, we got to get help.
-没人帮我们了  -希巴
- We're out of help. ‭- Sheba.
她觉得我在教唆一个恐怖分子
She's thinks I'm abetting a terrorist.
那你就得说服她你没有
Well, then you have to convince her that you're not.
你得走了 爸爸
You have got to leave, Papa.
-我不会跑的  -政府已经被锁定了
- I will not run away.- The government is being targeted.
你已经被锁定了
You are being targeted.
-我只是一个无名小卒  -你对他们来说也代表政府
- I'm a no one.- You are government to them.
你不理解作为一个也门人
You don't understand being a Yemeni.
怎么会在国家最需要你的时候逃走呢
You would run away when she needs you the most?
我知道 如果我们死了 对这个国家没有任何好处
I understand that we are no good to this country dead.
爸爸 会有机会的 我们去国外
Papa, there will come a time. We go abroad,
重组一个流亡政府
regroup with an exile government.
哪有钱 孩子
With what money, girl?
起码得花两年的薪水
It would cost two years' salary.
比起逃走我宁愿面对敌人 死而无憾
I'd rather die with my face to the enemy than to run away.
爸爸
Papa...
我建议
I suggest you leave
你快点离开这个国家
this country as quickly as you can.
他在这干吗
What's he doing here?
我朋友需要你的帮助
My friend needs your help.
我已经帮过了
I gave him my help.
你没告诉我 他和我的敌人一起工作
You didn't tell me he was working with the enemy.
你口中所说的你的兄弟
This man you claim is your brother,
坎尼尔·奥提斯 他和叛党是一伙的
Kaniel Outis, worked with the rebels.
-他叫迈克尔·斯科菲尔德  -我不管他叫什么
- His name's Michael Scofield. - I don't care!
不是坎尼尔·奥提斯
Not Kaniel Outis!
你说什么都没用
There's nothing you can say to me that will
我是不会帮你的
make me help you, okay?
是吗
Is that right?
这些钱足够能让你的家人离开这个国家吗
This enough to get your family out of the country?
先把我送去这里
Deliver me this first.
准备好了吗 亲爱的
Ready, love?
-那是什么  -那是...是
- What's that? - It's, uh... it's
是林肯叔叔发来的
something your Uncle Lincoln sent.
我不想走 我想和你在一起
I don't want to go. I want to stay with you.
你该去学校了
You got to go to school.
你一放学 我就在这儿等着你
And I'm gonna be right here when the bell rings.
好吗 然后你走过来
Okay? You walk down those steps,
一脚跳进车里 好吗
you hop straight into the car. Yeah?
我爱你
I love you.
祝你今天愉快
Make it a great day.
我收到了信
I got the note.
迈克尔 我收到了信
I got the note, Michael.
我们会把你救出来的
We're going to get you out of here.
听着 我不叫迈克尔
Look, my name isn't Michael,
我也不认识你
and I don't know who you are.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你知道我是个著名经济学家吗
You know I'm a noted economist?
我是说 报纸上这么说的
I mean, that's what it says in the paper.
"著名经济学家在家遇袭 "
"Noted Economist Attacked in Home."
我都不知道经济学家还能上新闻
I didn't even know economists made the news.
希望没有下次
That's the first and last time, hopefully.
我试着理顺思路
I've been trying to piece this thing together.
你还记得那些政府的人吗
You remember those government guys,
那些智囊团的人
those think tank guys,
想让我来解决博弈论
trying to pick my brain about game theory,
他们怎么能把那种理论当作外交政策呢
how they could use it for foreign policy?
你非常讨厌他们 对吧
Yeah, you bored the hell out of 'em, right?
是的 不过 我是不是听到了一些
Yeah, okay, but I mean, did I hear something
-我不该听到的事  -我不知道 你听到了吗
- I shouldn't have? - I don't know. Did you?
比如说 谁杀了肯尼迪
Like who shot JFK?
我没开玩笑呢
I am trying to be serious here.
没有 你服用了太多止痛剂
No, you're doped up on painkillers
而且 你想太多了
and you're thinking too much.
我保证 这和你没任何关系
I promise this has nothing to do with you.
你休息吧 我准备去...
You rest. I'm going to ...
出去办点事
I'm gonna run some errands,
然后回去看你 好吗
and then I'm gonna come visit you, okay?
好的 爱你
Okay. Love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
好的 没问题 谢谢
Okay, no problem. Thanks.
你好 我...之前打过电话 是有关一个失踪的美国公民
Hi. I...I called earlier about a missing U.S. Citizen
-他现在在中东  -我记得 我是亨利·岸田
- in the Middle East. - Yes. I'm Henry Kishida.
我带你去负责人的办公室
Let me walk you to the director's office.
你的情况有些特殊
It's an unusual situation,
想必你也明白
which you can appreciate,
你丈夫已经公证死亡
since your husband is declared legally dead,
并且你提到的那个人
and the person that you're referring to
用的是另一个名字
goes by another name.
亨利 交给我吧
I'll take it from here, Henry.
莎拉 你怎么样
How are you, Sara?
凯勒曼
Kellerman?
那我就先走了 如果有什么需要 请尽管告诉我
I'll leave you two be. Let me know if you need anything, sir.
抱歉
Sorry, how did I
怎么又是你
end up with you again?
你来请求国务院的帮助
You asked for the State Department's help.
我需要国务院的帮助 不是你的帮助
I wanted the State Department, not you.
你身份太多了
Yeah, you've lived
我不知道你到底是谁
so many lives, I don't know who you are.
对你来说也是一样 不是吗
That'd be a consistent theme for you, wouldn't it, given that
嫁给了一个从没存在过的人
you were married to a man who never existed?
这话什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
意思是 你应该进去坐坐 让我来开导你
It means you should come in and let me enlighten you
好好讲讲和迈克尔·斯科菲尔德有关的事...
to all things Michael Scofield...
或者说 坎尼尔·奥提斯
Or should I say Kaniel Outis?
最好别喝瓶装水
You shouldn't drink
里面有二恶英 双酚A  [二恶英 有毒 用于塑料制品中 双酚A 有毒 可溶于水]
bottled water...the dioxins, the BPAs in there...
多谢关心
I'm touched by your concern.
坐吧
Have a seat.
不了 谢谢
Good, thank you.
莎拉...
You know, Sara...
我们俩...过去关系波折
...you and I have... a checkered past.
不过 我现在是个无趣的人啦 并且...
But I am evermore a boring guy now, and...
生活让我变得更加沉稳 真的
mellowed by life, trust me.
如果你想告诉我和迈克尔有关的消息
If you have something you want to tell me
我很乐意好好倾听
about Michael, I'd sure love to hear it.
你打电话求助时候 岸田接手了你的事...
Okay. When your call came in and Kishida processed it...
大概是其中出现了些关键词
Well, let's just say there are certain keywords
让我们不得不注意起来
that get our system buzzing pretty quickly.
坎尼尔·奥提斯...
Kaniel Outis...
其实
Actually, can't stand it
你那样喝水 我实在是受不了
watching you drink out of that.
岸田
Hey, Kishida?
给莎拉倒杯水 行吗
Could you bring Sara a glass for her water, please?
谢谢你
Thank you.
坎尼尔·奥提斯...
Kaniel Outis...
是个出名的恐怖分子
is a known terrorist,
和伊斯兰国有牵连
ties to ISIL, wanted in the killing
谋杀了一位高级CIA官员
of a senior CIA official.
-迈克尔不是杀手  -看
- Michael's no killer. - You see,
这就是问题所在
that's the problem.
因为坎尼尔·奥提斯就是杀手
Because Kaniel Outis is.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
并且...
And...
这是坎尼尔·奥提斯
this is Kaniel Outis.
可笑至极
That's ridiculous.
国务院的档案里
The record here at State says
坎尼尔·奥提斯长这个样
that... that's Kaniel Outis's face.
但你我都清楚迈克尔·斯科菲尔德是谁
but you and I both know who Michael Scofield was.
不 那只是回忆
No, that's just a memory.
现在官方的记录...历史数据...
The official record-- history--
不是那么说的了
it says otherwise now.
现在 想想背后操纵的人真的很可怕
Now, that's scary, to think who could be behind that.
因为只有一个强大的人物
Because only somebody very formidable
才有能力
would be capable
名正言顺地将一个人的身份转换成另一个人的
of officially turning one man into another.
那得是个天才才行...像迈克尔那样的
It would take a genius... like Michael.
你是在暗示我是他干的吗
You're insinuating that he did this?
他消失了
He disappeared,
就这样离他的生活而去吗
just quit on his life?
我和你一样渴求答案
I want answers just like you do.
谁有能力这样做呢
Who's capable of this?
这世界上一共也没几个
Only a handful of people in the world.
萨拉 萨拉
Sara? Sara!
我算了一下 我们大概有一两天的时间
I figure we got a day, maybe two,
最多了 离开这破地方
tops, to get out of this hole.
这样看来
At that point,
我们不是死在枪林弹雨里
either the shelling gets us...
就是被伊斯兰国弄死
or ISIL does.
这些情况你完全无动于衷吗
Does any of this phase you at all?
我们都快要全部死在这了
The fact that we're gonna die in here?
我们不会死的 我们都会出去的
We're not gonna die. We're still getting out.
所有人
All of us.
怎么走啊 走房顶吗
How's that? The roof?
-房顶走不了了  -就是要走房顶
- The roof ain't happening. - The roof is happening.
我们没时间再想一个逃脱计划出来了
We don't have time to come up with another escape plan.
所以你的确在紧张
So you are nervous.
棒极了 我就知道我要出事
Great, now I know I'm in deep crap.
我这么做就只是为了钱
I'm only doing this for the money.
不要觉得我们忽然就是朋友了
Don't think you and I are suddenly good.
你就把我送到酋长那就行
You just deliver me the sheik.
酋长们离这很远
The sheiks are well away from here.
在沙漠深处
High desert.
我也从来没听说过谁
And I've never heard of one
被叫做光之酋长的
being referred to as Sheik of Light.
意思就是 这也许是个暗语
Which means it's probably a code.
他了解你兄弟
She knows your brother.
这块胶带...
This tape--
是唯一不属于这张纸的部分
it's the only thing that doesn't belong.
你兄弟在和我们猜谜语啊
Your brother speaks in riddles,
是吧 这可能是布莱叶盲文
does he? ‭Maybe it's Braille
或者 摩斯电码
or, Morse.
或者就是数字
Or just numbers.
我觉得是个电话号
I think it's a phone number.
语音信箱
Voice mail.
穆哈默德·阿尔·突尼斯
Mohammad El-Tunis.
萨那电气工程部的总监
Director of Electrical Works in Sana'a.
电气工程部总监
Director of Electrical Works.
"光之酋长"
"Sheik of Light."
感谢你花时间见我们
Thanks for taking the time to see us.
大家都去哪了
Where is everybody?
他们都提前逃跑了
They are fleeing ahead of the advance.
我们也在试着找总监
We have been trying to reach him.
我们只知道他去郊区了
All we know is that he went to the suburbs
要找他女儿
to try to find his daughter.
你有她地址吗
Do you have an address for her?
我们打电话给她  但是没人接
We tried calling her, but no answer.
这是地址
Address is here.
你不会是想要找到他吧
You are not going to try to find him, are you?
那就祝愿真主保佑你们吧
God be with you, then.
地址给你们圈出来了
Circled the address.
你们好运吧
Good luck.
你和我们一起去
You're coming with us.
你要是觉得我会去郊区的话
If you think I'm going into the suburbs,
那你一定是疯了
you're crazy.
郊区怎么了
What's wrong with the suburbs?
郊区就在那边
The suburbs are out there.
战争前线
The front line of the war.
很高兴认识你 本杰明
Nice knowing you, Benjamin.
我希望下次
I hope next time
是在好一些的境况下见到你
it's under better circumstances.
-钱拿来  -你得把我们送过检查关口
- Pay up. - You have to get us past the checkpoint.
我们两个美国人 没你去不了
Two Americans-- we'll never make it without you.
我不想死
I am not getting myself killed.
给钱
Pay up.
送我们去见酋长
Deliver the sheik.
然后就给你钱
Then you get your money.
上车
Get in.
喂
Yes?
你应该看看你的邮箱 萨拉
You should check your e-mail, Sara.
这是什么啊
What am I looking at?
是一个猎人四年前拍下的镜头
Footage captured by a hunter four years ago.
那些挂在树上的运动传感器里有一个
One of those motion sensor devices you hang on trees,
间间断断地拍摄猎物的照片
takes intermittent photos of prey.
那个猎人有天早上看到了这些照片
Hunter comes out one morning, finds these images.
这个就是我跟你说过的那个杀人事件
This is the killing I was telling you about.
受害者是哈兰·盖恩斯 中情局的副主任
The victim's Harlan Gaines, Deputy Chief of the CIA.
而杀手是
And the killer...
你看得到
well, you can see,
也就是我们叫做迈克尔·斯科菲尔德的人
it's who we call Michael Scofield,
或者说 坎尼尔·奥提斯 或者...
or Kaniel Outis, or...
这和他们对林肯设的局完全吻合
This is exactly what they did to Lincoln.
但是第二天就有血证了
And then there's the blood evidence the next day.
坎尼尔或是迈克尔或是管他谁飞去了也门
Kaniel or Michael or whatever gets on a flight to Yemen.
我们差点就在他落地的时候抓到他了
We almost nail him when he lands.
他逃跑了
He gets away.
但他的行李还在
His luggage doesn't
行李中的衣服满是盖恩斯的血
and Gaines' blood is all over the clothes inside.
这是无可辩驳的证据
The evidence is overwhelming.
不管你叫他什么
Whatever name you want to call him,
迈克尔都是杀人犯 萨拉
Michael's a murderer, Sara.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
你好吗
You all right?
这副老身板吗
Oh, this old thing?
我挺好的
Yeah, I'm doing fine.
怎么了
What's going on?
我需要你的建议
I need your advice.
也许你不是很想
It's probably something you're not gonna
和我谈这个
want to talk about.
我现在真的很需要你的清晰思路
I could really use your clarity right now.
是有关迈克尔的
It's about Michael.
还是很想知道他是怎么塞进去的
Still want to know how he got that in here.
脱光了和狱警拥抱
Hugging naked with the guards.
只有那样 对吗
Got to be, right?
什么情况
What the hell is that?
"我们是冠军"
"We are the Champions."
像现在这样被困在尿壶里 还会去看皇后乐队的演出吗
You get stuck in a Porta-Potty like this, you go Queen?
我是说
I mean, where are the girls
难道不是应该看小黄片吗 对吧
riding the washing machines, right?
再看我的屏幕 它就会刺进你的眼球里
Look at my screen again, this goes in your eye.
你知道的 这世界从不缺惊艳
You know, the world never ceases to amaze.
当你被困在一个中东的监狱里时
You get stuck in a Middle Eastern prison,
最大的混蛋却是个韩国人
the biggest S.O.B. Is a Korean.
他戒断症发作了
He's in withdrawal.
你知道吗 他是这个世界上
You know, he's the biggest collector
皇后乐队用品的最大收藏家
of Queen paraphernalia in the world.
据说他在首尔的房子是佛瑞迪·莫库瑞的圣祠[皇后乐队主唱]
They say his house in Seoul is a shrine to Freddy Mercury.
但他怎么会在这里
And he got in here how?
身份盗窃
Identity theft.
显然他过去就坐在他的沙发上
Apparently he used to sit on his couch,
黑掉世界各地的高净值账户
hack high net worth accounts all over the world.
把钱变成了一堆收集品 悍马 直升机
Turned it into a collection of Hummers, helicopters
当然还有佛瑞迪·莫库瑞的骨灰
and, apparently, Freddy Mercury's ashes.
等等 你是说尸体焚化后的骨灰吗
Wait, you mean like his burnt-up body?
故事的内容是佛瑞迪被火化了 但是他的骨灰失踪了
The story is Freddy's cremated, but his ashes go missing.
至今没人知道他的骨灰在哪
To this day no one knows where they are.
贾曾经跟我承认过 在他人生巅峰时 他买下了骨灰
Ja admitted to me once when he was high he bought them.
两百万美元
Two million bucks.
他在起居室里摆放了皇后乐队主唱的骨灰
He's got Queen's lead singer in his family room.
你到底是怎么知道这些的
How exactly do you know all this?
我问的他
I asked him.
他戒断症没有发作时 还是个不错的人
He's a real mensch when he's not in withdrawal.
我完全不知道你和他说过话
I didn't know you talked to him.
真厉害
Amazing.
就像我刚以为自己了解你的计划 但其实并没有
Just when I think I know your game, I don't.
你知道我的计划 维普
You know my game, Whip.
看 就像这样 "维普"
See, right there, "Whip."
我甚至不知道你为什么这么叫我
I don't even know why you call me that.
因为你是我的右手
Because you're my whip hand.
我最后的王牌
My ace in the hole.
嗯 当然 好吧
Yeah, sure, okay.
你看 在博弈论中 事物都具有两面性
See, in game theory, it serves you to be two-faced.
成为每个人的朋友 直到你不再是他们的朋友
Be everyone's friend till the moment you're not.
当他们不喜欢你时 你让他们非常喜欢你
You make them love you so much that when they're up against it,
他们的忠诚就会使他们做出
their loyalty will make them act
违背他们最佳利益的选择
against their own best interests.
这就是博弈论
That's game theory.
一个无情却又合理的赢法
A cold, rational focus on winning.
即使那会损害别人的利益
Even if it's at everyone else's expense.
我想要知道的是 他想得到什么
What I'm trying to understand is what he stands to gain.
抛下他的家庭 还有... 他的新身份
Leaving his family, and... and the new identity.
透过你告诉我的那些简短描述 他是与众不同的人
According to the little you've told me, he was different.
总是事先计划好 对吗
Always an agenda, right?
是的
Yeah.
我是说 他显然很爱你
I mean, he apparently loved you.
他当然爱你
Of course he loved you.
他怎么可能不爱你
How could he not?
但他同样也需要你为他打开
But he also wanted you to open that door
监狱里的那道门
in the prison for him.
我是说 真正的博弈论
I mean, true game theory,
每件事 每个人
everything, everyone
都具有偶然性
is a contingency.
你遇见一些人 你让他们走进了你的生活
You meet people, you bring them into your life
你让他们渗透你的生活 直到你需要
and you keep them percolating until the moment
利用这段关系来获得自己的利益
you need to manipulate the relationship to your advantage.
我不是在评价谁 你知道的 我不会那么做
I'm not judging, you know? That's not my thing.
-我知道  -你了解我 但是...
-I know. -You know me. But...
计划被计算的那么精准那么长远
schema as deep and as calculating as that can,
最终
in the end,
会将一个人变成疯子
spin a man off into madness.
他起初可能会想 为了更伟大的利益
He might initially think smaller evils are okay
一点小错无伤大雅
in the service of a greater good.
就像带着林肯越狱
Like breaking Lincoln out of prison.
但是正义与邪恶的博弈可能会变得混乱
But the dance of good and evil could become jumbled,
然后他自身的利益就会成为
and the manipulation itself becomes
最重要的事
the most important thing.
成为赢家
Becomes about winning
比到底该不该赢更重要了
rather than whether the game should be won at all.
我还没见过你像现在这样害怕过
I don't think I've seen you this scared before.
他们说 在斋月 作为宽恕的表现
They say, for Ramadan, as an act of forgiveness,
他们会释放
they're going to release
那边隔离区的所有囚犯
all prisoners from solitary over there
放回到普通囚犯中
back into general population.
没有比这更糟的事了
Worst of the worst.
伊斯兰国的狂热信徒
ISIL fanatics.
阿布·拉马尔
Abu Ramal.
他们会杀了我 你知道的
They're going to kill me, you know.
政府判了我20年
Government gave me 20 years
就因为我是同性恋
for homosexuality.
但那里面的怪物
But the monsters in there,
拉马尔和他的手下
Ramal and his men,
他们不会让我活过20分钟
won't let me live 20 minutes.
请你告诉我
Please tell me
你依旧打算把我们从这里带出去
you still plan on getting us out of here.
你原本应该让监狱断电
You were responsible for killing the lights,
但是你的光之酋长刚好在错误的时间
and then your Sheik of Light went missing
失踪了
at exactly the wrong time.
我不知道他发生了什么
I don't know what happened to him.
也许我能找到别的方法
Maybe I can find another way.
你确实还能做一些事情
There is something you could do.
给我一片口香糖
Give me a piece of that gum.
一片口香糖能换我们离开监狱吗
Piece of gum is going to get us out of prison?
它会启动进程
It'll start the process.
有时候 朋友 我真的不知道应该相信什么
Sometimes, my friend, I can't tell which is bigger,
你的计划 还是你的谎言
your plans or your lies.
我觉得你在针对我 你叫我骗子
I take that personally, you calling me a liar.
然后我会让你知道 就像蝴蝶效应一样
And I'm gonna show you, just like the butterfly's wings,
这片口香糖会引发一系列的事情
this piece of gum is gonna start a sequence of events
然后在地球的另一端 圆满落幕
that will finish on the other side of the world.
电池 拜托
Battery, please.
监狱打火机
Prison lighter.
维普 我需要你的袜子
Whip, I need your socks.
西德 水壶
Sid, water can.
外面怎么样了
How we doing out there?
没被发现 快一点
We're all good. Quick though.
好了
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
你确定要这么做吗
You sure about this?
没时间了
There's no time left.
这城市快沦陷了
The city's about to collapse.
非常时期 非常手段
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
搞定
Got it.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
快去 快去
Go, go, go.
警卫
Guards!
这里有人生病了
We got a sick one in here.
什么情况
What is this?
他烧得厉害 得去医务室
He's burning up, he needs the infirmary.
拜托了
Please.
就是这儿了
This is it.
政府管辖范围的边界
Limit of government control.
过了这儿就是伊斯兰国的领域了
Anything after this is ISIL territory.
停车
Stop.
我来跟他们说
Let me do the talking.
他说我们几个是西方人加一个女人
He's says us being Westerners, a woman...
多半有去无回
we go inside, we are not coming back.
他们不让我们进去
They're not letting us through.
告诉他 我用五百美元跟他打赌 我们会毫发无损地回来
Tell him I bet $500 bucks we'll make it back in one piece.
他没有五百块跟你赌
He doesn't have $500 to bet.
没关系
It doesn't matter.
如果我们回不来 他就把钱留下
We don't make it back, he keeps it.
他说我们在自寻死路
He says we have a death wish.
很好
Fine.
这座城市原来很漂亮 生机勃勃的
The city used to be beautiful, alive.
看看他们都把它糟蹋成什么样子了
Look what they've done to it.
他们把阿布·拉马尔画到墙上了
They're putting up portraits of Abu Ramal.
看来他被关在奥杰吉厄监狱之后
He's only gotten more powerful
变得更强大了
since he got locked up in Ogygia.
要是他出狱了 那就只有真主保佑了
God help us if he gets out.
伊斯兰国
ISIL.
我们得停车了 趴下
We're gonna get stopped. Get down.
马上
Down now.
藏好
Cover up.
不可思议
Can't believe this.
我认识他
I know him.
雷扎
Reza.
现在我叫阿布·埃米尔
It's Abu Amir now.
你来郊区这里做什么 希巴
What are you doing in the suburbs, Sheba?
走错了
Took a wrong turn.
你把你的头发包起来了
You got your hair covered up.
很好
That's good.
你终于找到你的真主了吗
Finally find God?
和你信仰的真主不一样
Not your God.
世上只有一个真主
There is only one God.
我们会拿下这座城市 你知道的
We're gonna take the city, you know.
如果你表现好...
You be nice...
或许我会让你做我的女人
maybe I'll make a good woman of you.
原谅你的不好
Forgive the devil in you.
不如我马上掉头
Why don't I just turn around now?
我们原谅彼此
We forgive each other.
原谅对方曾经出现在自己生命里
Forget each other ever existed.
美人没那么容易被遗忘
Beauty is not so easily forgotten.
罗密欧
Lover boy
我们得走了
We have to go.
政府军到阿克萨公园了
Government's moving in at Aksa Park.
放她走
Cut her loose.
滚出我们的地盘
Get the hell off our territory.
他们走了
They are gone.
我们得抓紧
We have to hurry.
幸好他刚刚没当场杀了我
We're lucky he didn't kill me right then.
为什么
Why?
或许以后再告诉你吧
Maybe I'll tell you one day.
他们在摧毁我们的城市
They're destroying our city.
你伊斯兰国的朋友在摧毁我们的城市
Your ISIL friends are destroying our city.
而你却来这里
And you come in here
希望我们帮你
wanting help.
只要给我拿点药什么的
Just give me a little something.
这里有医生吗 我要烧成灰了
Is there a doctor here? I'm burning up.
你贩卖枪支的时候
You should have thought about that
你刺杀无辜人民的时候
when you supplied guns to them,
你就应该想到这一点
assassinated good men.
那些指控子虚乌有
Those charges were misunderstanding
坎尼尔·奥提斯说他是冤枉的
Kaniel Outis says it was misunderstanding
那你一到这个监狱就想越狱
Was it also misunderstanding when you
也是被冤枉的吗
tried to escape the moment you got into this prison?
一个清白的人不用逃跑 他会请律师
An honest man doesn't try to escape. He asks for a lawyer.
但你...你进来的第一个星期就想越狱
But you... you tried to escape the very first week.
要是我做主的话 恐怕我会让你在这里孤独终老
I doubt that you would be in solitary forever if it was up to me.
地址在街区尽头
The address at the end of the block.
叛军...
Rebels...
就在房子前面
right in front of the house.
去你妈的
Son of a bitch.
这个国家哪件事顺利过
Anything easy in this country?
问题在于酋长在里面吗
The question is: is the sheik even inside?
只有一个办法才能知道了
Only one way to find out.
如果他们发现我们在这里
They find us up here,
我们无从解释
there's no explaining ourselves.
必死无疑
We're all dead.
安静
Quiet.
你们...你们不是伊斯兰国的
You... You are not ISIL?
不是 不过 你是默罕默德·阿尔·突尼斯 对吗
No. But you're Mohammad El-Tunis, I take it?
我们从市中心的 来带你离开
We are from the city center. We are here to get you out.
不带上我女儿我是不会走的
Not without my daughter.
可以 她在哪里
We can bring her. Where is she?
-她在那里  -哪里
- She's out there. - Where?
在街对面校舍的地下室里
In the basement of the schoolyard, across the street.
被伊斯兰国的人关起来了
Pinned since ISIL arrived.
我来这带她走
I came to get her out.
结果我也被关起来了
And I got pinned, too.
不是我乌鸦嘴 林肯 不过我觉得
I hate to say it, Linc, but I think we might've
我们可能也被关在这里了
just got pinned as well.
你还好吗
You okay?
你那样子就好像你可以用一点锋利工具
You look like you could use a few sharp edges
保护自己一样
knocked off your world.
你自己看起来也一副怂样啊
You don't look so good yourself.
你想从也门搞到什么药物
Say what you want about Yemen,
他们对药物一点也不小气
they're not shy about prescriptions.
这可是好东西 含吗啡的药片
It's the good stuff. Morphine derivative.
我要用你的手机 还要一张信用卡
I need access to your cell phone and a credit card number.
做什么
Why?
点份披萨
I want to order a pizza.
有扇后门
There's a back door,
通往校舍 快走
toward the schoolhouse. Come on.
来不及了
Too late.
上房顶
Go to the rooftops.
他们都在车那边
They're all over the Rover.
-我们过不去的  -我可以把那辆小货车开来
- We'll never get to it. - ‭I can get in that pickup,
再顺便给他们弄点麻烦
make a ruckus on my way out.
幸运地话 他们都会来追我
Any luck, they'll be all over me.
那你们就有机会跑到车那里了
Then you got a clean shot to the Rover.
快走 走
Go. Go!
我不走
I'm not leaving
不能抛下我女儿啊
without my daughter.
你不明白伊斯兰国的人为了调教她们
You don't know what ISIL will do to her
会做出什么事来
for educating those girls.
我会把她带出来的 我向你保证
I'll get her out, I promise.
-走啊  -好 好
-Go! -Okay! Okay.
你爸爸让我来接你走
Your father sent me. I'm getting you out of here.
快点 快走
Come on! Come on!
趴下 别动
Get down! Stay down!
他必须要逃出来
He's got to make it.
你知道你必须要逃出来 加油
You know you got to make it. Come on.
他在那 在那呢
There he is! There he is!
欧耶 宝贝
Yeah, baby!
不 不 坏事了
Oh, no. This isn't good.
坏大事了
This isn't good.
这是政府的检查点
This government checkpoint.
他们会误认为我们是自杀式炸弹 我们必须要停车
They'll think we're suicide bombers. We have to stop.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
别开枪
Don't shoot at us!
别开枪 别开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
趴下
Stay down!
我也高兴
I'm so happy, too.
对不起...
Forgive me, uh...
她们的父母都被杀了
Their parents have been killed.
我还没找到帮助她们的法子
I'm trying to figure out how I can help them.
她们可以暂时待在这里
They can stay here for now.
只要你告诉我 你跟奥杰吉厄监狱里哪个人有联系
As long as you tell me who you know in Ogygia,
还有他们为什么这么需要你
and why they want you so bad.
我有...
I'm a man with, uh...
几个麻烦孩子
troublesome children.
他们都很出色
They're beautiful.
只是对于这个国家可能思想太超前了
But perhaps too modern for this country.
我女儿想要教育女孩子
My daughter tries to educate girls.
我的儿子
And my son,
他爱上了另一个男人
he falls in love with another man.
被判了20年监禁在奥杰吉厄监狱
They gave him 20 years in Ogygia Prison.
我几周前去探视他
I went to visit him a few weeks ago.
他说 也许有办法逃出去
He said, maybe there is a way out.
而且我能帮上忙
A way I could help.
要是眼睁睁看着家人死
A man is not a man
那我还是什么男人
if he would let his family die.
你同意帮他
You agreed to help him.
怎么帮
How?
他说如果我能让监狱断电
He said if I could arrange a blackout,
他...他认识一个能帮他逃出去的人
he... he knew someone who could get him out.
美国人吗
An American?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我...我一周前就应该做的
I... I was supposed to do this a week ago,
但我女儿出了事
but then this happened with my daughter.
谢天谢地你找到了我们
Thank God you found us.
现在还有时间
There's still time to do it.
他们还在牢里等着你呢
They're waiting for you in there.
那我现在就得去
Then I have to go now.
他说我得在停电前
He said I was to give a signal
24小时给他们发信号
exactly 24 hours before the blackout.
让电流波动两次
I will pulse the power grid twice.
这城市可能撑不了24小时了
This city may not have 24 hours in it.
大伙 再见
Bye, guys.
再见
Bye.
都知道我看人眼光不好
God knows I'm no perfect judge of character,
但是 迈克尔
but Michael?
要是他们说的有一点是真的...
If any of what they're saying is true...
你还要再去了解 萨拉
So there's more to find out, Sara.
重要的是 你会挺过来的
I mean, the important thing is that you are gonna survive this,
不管真相怎么样
however it turns out.
我们会在这儿支持你的 好吗
And we're here for you. Okay?
-咱们走  -谢谢你
- Let's go. ‭- Thank you.
给我打电话
Call me, okay?
好的
Yeah.
你好 我能进去把迈克带走吗
Hey, can I just scoop Mike real quick?
所有的孩子都已经走了
All the kids have been released.
你没接到他吗
You don't have him?
迈克
Mike?
-我去这边找  -好的
- I'll go this way. ‭- Okay, yeah.
迈克
Mike?
嘿 你看见迈克了吗
Hey, hey, have you seen Mike?
迈克
Mike!
你...
There...
你干什么呢 吓死我了
What are you doing? You scared me.
我在找那个男人去哪儿了
I was looking for where the man went.
什么男人 宝贝
What man, baby?
给我这个的人
The man that gave me this.
送披萨的人
The pizza man.
The pizza man?
迈克尔
Michael.
你到底卷进了什么事
What are you into?
伊斯兰国每小时都在逼近
ISIL is getting closer by the hour.
那群造反的人也知道了
And the rebels in here know it.
等他们掌控了城市 会杀了我们所有人
When they take over, they'll kill all of us.
不忠的人 有罪的人 还有外国人
Infidels, the sinners, the foreigners.
老天爷
Praise Allah.
有人找到我爸了
Someone found my father.
那逃跑计划可以开始了
Means the escape is on.
现在开始24小时倒计时
24 hours from now.
估计来不及了
But this may be too late.
斋月开始了
Ramadan has begun.
狱警开始放囚犯了
The guards are releasing the prisoners.
阿布·拉马尔 还有他手下
Abu Ramal and his men,
他们会杀了我的
they'll kill me.
还有你
And you.
电影淘淘
WWW.DYTTBD.COM
更多电影美剧尽在（电影淘淘 www.dyttbd.com）